我们都非常直观地了解路径是什么。
We all have a pretty intuitive idea of what a path is.
我们认为它是从A地到B地的一种方式。
We consider it as a way of getting from place A to place B.
我们可以将它视为一组连接A到B的点;我们的一系列小步骤
We can consider it as a set of points that link A to B; a set of small steps that we
一路走来。
take along the way.
路径是空间构造。
A path is a spatial construct.
它说明了我们如何通过世界从A到B，但它没有说
It says something about how we get from A to B through the world but it doesn't say
关于我们应该多快移动它的任何事情。
anything about how quickly we should move along it.
没有时间概念。
There's no notion of time.
另一方面，轨迹包括从A到A的路径和时间表
A trajectory on the other hand comprises a path and a schedule for getting from A to
B.所以沿着这条道路有一个时间或速度的概念。
B. So there is a notion of time or speed along the path.
这是我需要在特定时间内完成的一系列要点。
It's a set of points that I need to be at by a particular time.
在我的MATLAB工作空间中，我有两个姿势表示为4x4齐次变换
In my MATLAB work space, I have got two poses represented as 4x4 homogeneous transformation
矩阵。
matrices.
由工作空间变量T0表示的第一个姿势没有旋转并且具有它
The first pose represented by the workspace variable T0, has got no rotation and has its
起源于世界坐标系的原点。
origin at the origin of the world coordinate frame.
由工作空间变量T1表示的第二个帖子在x方向上包括1的集合
The second post represented by the work space variable T1, comprises set of 1 in the x direction
在y方向上的图2和在z方向上的3和由辊间距描述的取向
2 in the y direction and 3 in the z direction and an orientation described by roll pitch
偏航角分别为0.6,0.8和1.4弧度。
yaw angles 0.6, 0.8 and 1.4 radians respectively.
我们可以想象出这些姿势。
And we can visualize each of these poses.
我可以绘制姿势T0，我们可以看到它的起源是世界的起源
I can plot the pose T0 and we can see there its origin is at the origin of the world
帧。
frame.
它的轴与世界框架对齐。
And its axes are aligned with the world frame.
我可以绘制另一个姿势T1，我们可以看到它的起源不是原点
I can plot the other pose T1 and we can see that its origin is not at the origin of the
世界参考系及其轴与参考轴不平行。
world reference frame and its axes are not parallel to the reference axes.
现在我可以为从姿势T0到姿势T1的运动设置动画，我们可以看到我们的坐标
Now I can animate the motion that goes from pose T0 to pose T1 and we can see our coordinate
框架正在平移和旋转，以便从姿势T0移动到姿势T1。所以这
frame is translating and rotating in order to move from pose T0 to pose T1. So this
当我谈到一个从一个姿势到另一个姿势的平滑运动的轨迹时，我的意思是
is what I mean when I talked about a trajectory which is smooth motion from one pose to the
下一个。
next.
弄清楚如何做到这一点是本讲座的主题。
Figuring out how to do this is the subject of this lecture.